<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>OSLC Fest</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on OSLC Fest</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>OSLC through the formative years</title>
      <link>/program/oslc-through-the-formative-years/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/program/oslc-through-the-formative-years/</guid>
      <description>10 years ago, OSLC was just coming into existence. This presentation will explore the dynamics that led to OSLC&amp;rsquo;s formation, discussing the threads of technology and community, and how they wove together to deliver key elements of an open product lifecycle integration solution. We&amp;rsquo;ll then travel along OSLC&amp;rsquo;s evolution, remembering (or perhaps discovering) some of the steps along the way, with the goal of understanding OSLC&amp;rsquo;s contributions while absorbing lessons for the continuing journey.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Services, Interoperability, and Hypermedia: A possible Future</title>
      <link>/program/open-services-interoperability-and-hypermedia/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/program/open-services-interoperability-and-hypermedia/</guid>
      <description>This talk will focus on what it means to design and support &amp;ldquo;Open Services&amp;rdquo; and the role hypermedia might play in advancing open systems. Author, speaker, and trainer Mike Amundsen will pose a series of questions aimed at identifying characteristics of open, collaborative ecosystems. For example, what are the pillars of open, interoperable systems and what can the last 20 years of the WWW teach us about what works &amp;ndash; and what does not work &amp;ndash; when creating specifications for an open, collaborative system?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>